- Hello, I'm Dr. Charles Severance
from the University of Michigan School of Information.
Welcome to my introductory Python course on Udemy.
This course is designed for people
who want to learn programming,
even if they've never written a line of code.
There is no math and no algebra.
All you need is curiosity and a willingness
to be patient with yourself as you learn.
I've taught Python to millions of learners around the world,
and my goal is to explain not only what to type
but why programming works the way that it does.
These days, artificial intelligence
can make typing code trivial,
but you still need to understand how programming works
if you want to use AI effectively in software development.
Learning to program is hard,
and I have never forgotten how difficult
and confusing my first programming course was.
This course addresses that difficulty
directly throughout the course and helps you work through it
step by step until you begin to feel
and think like a programmer.
We begin with basic ideas of variables and expressions,
conditional execution, functions, and loops.
Then we move into strings, data structures, and files.
You'll watch short lectures, examine working examples,
and write Python programs yourself.
This course is designed to take you from a complete beginner
to someone who is ready to write simple Python programs,
and more importantly, someone who feels confident enough
to take another programming course.
So please watch my free preview lectures,
and I hope you will join me
in this introductory Python course on Udemy.